Advanced Class
Next up...
Wakaba, who's moved up
to the advanced class.
Yes.
My name is Aoi Wakaba.
I'm an elf hailing from Liefgard,
a now-bygone treetop city.
A treetop city?
Where is that, Mr. Hitoma?
I don't know, either.
The reason I want to be human
is to let everyone know of my beauty.
I'll become number one in the
human world, not just in Liefgard.
Wonderful, don't you think?
Huh? Sure...
She sure is confident in herself.
Prince Waka was like this all the time
in the intermediate class, too.
Now for... Okonogi.
Got it.
I'm Maki Okonogi.
I'm descended from oni.
The reason I wanna be human...
Um...
I forgot.
What?
That was a lie.
You were lying?
The reason I wanna be human
is because I don't wanna lie.
Because you don't want to lie?
Listen up, Okonogi.
Not all humans are good people.
There are plenty of humans who lie.
But you want to become human
just so that you don't lie?
Really? Then I don't wanna.
Huh?
That's a lie.
I'm an honest liar.
Is that right?
Sure, okay.
Let's work hard until you graduate.
Sure thing.
Did you really understand it, Mr. Hitoma?
What Miss Okonogi said earlier.
Yep.
I get now that
I don't understand her at all.
Huh?
The director let her enroll as a student,
so she must have a good reason.
Let's take our time getting to know her.
Yes!
Episode 12
The Misanthrope and Falsehood Found Nigh
What was it you wanted
to discuss, Mr. Hitoma?
Haneda, was it your idea
to have Haruna work here?
That's really only half right.
Half?
All I did was provide her with the chance.
Ms. Haruna was the one
who took it of her own will.
Just as you did when you chose our school.
Haneda, what is it you want from us?
Nothing in particular.
If you perform your duties
as teachers, that's all I need.
You and Ms. Haruna may share a past,
but she doesn't seem to begrudge you.
Or so she says, anyway...
Isn't that for the best, then?
I'd like nothing better than for you to
work together to guide our students.
Including me.
You as well?
I want to graduate one day
and become human, too.
I really mean it.
So I'll be in your hands, Mr. Hitoma.
Advanced Class
Okay, I'm handing back your tests
from the other day.
Could be better.
How'd you do, Maki?
I got a perfect score.
Seriously?!
I was lying.
What a stupid lie.
I actually got a zero.
I don't remember your grades
being so poor, Maki.
That was a lie.
You had me worried.
If you were telling the truth,
you'd have to take remedial lessons.
If I get a zero, I can be alone
with Mr. Rei for remedial lessons?!
Not happening.
I'd leave it to Ms. Haruna
if that happened.
Miss Okonogi's still telling lots of lies.
I'm used to it now, though.
I think of it as a speech quirk now,
so it doesn't bother me anymore.
It really doesn't bother you, does it?
When your students lie.
Ms. Haruna.
Yes?
You're really fine with
what happened back then?
Are you just trying to
put on a brave face?
Can I say what's really on my mind?
Mr. Hitoma.
I'm angry at you.
Didn't I tell you already?
We should forget about what happened.
We can't change the past.
We can only look to the future.
You know what my name is, right?
Mirai Haruna.
Mirai, as in "future."
Let's just think about
the future from here on out.
Yeah, I guess...
Okay!
Final Exams
1. Social Studies
2. Japanese
3. Math
Enjoying some sun, Okonogi?
It sure is warm out today.
What? It's cold.
Oh, I guess it's chilly with the wind.
I was lying.
I'm glad you weren't cold.
Wouldn't want you getting sick.
Mr. Hitoma, you don't seem to
care that I'm a liar.
You think?
Yeah. You never get mad at me.
It's not like your lies
ever cause any trouble.
There's no reason to be mad.
Hey, Mr. Hitoma.
You see, the truth is...
I can tell when other people lie.
Just kidding. That's a lie.
You were lying?!
I thought you might
really have that ability.
What were things like
before you came here, Okonogi?
Well, I was living with my mom.
But well, back in grade school,
some things got out of hand.
And well, that's why I came here.
Can you tell me a little more about that?
Well, another girl in my class
did something bad.
And she told a lie to keep it secret.
A lie?
I pointed out that she was lying.
Then they figured out
that I could see through lies...
Including some powerful people...
And then my mom told me
where to find this school.
Okonogi, does that mean you really...
Mr. Hitoma.
Are you basking in the sun?
You see, I was asking Mr. Hitoma
for some advice.
Mr. Hitoma's a wonderful
and reliable teacher, isn't he?
Ms. Mirai, you're a good,
hardworking teacher, too.
I'm happy to hear that
you think of me that way!
Crouch down!
Like this?
Now that's a good girl.
Thank you very much...?
Ms. Mirai, why'd you become a teacher?
I wanted to become just like Mr. Hitoma.
Hey, why don't we...
all take a field trip sometime?
A field trip?
You mean a date outdoors with Mr. Rei?
I'm pretty sure she doesn't.
We do have hands-on lessons
where we learn about the human world,
but they all take place on school grounds.
It's not the same as getting to interact
with real humans outside the barrier.
Sounds great!
I want to try one of every
convenience store's signature products!
Are we even allowed
to go outside the school?
We did it two years ago.
Playing by the river in the summer.
That sounds nice! I'm so jealous!
I wanna go play somewhere off-campus, too!
Got it.
There's a special off-campus permit within
two kilometers if you're with a teacher,
so I'll ask the principal for one.
But wouldn't it be bad if people
found out about their true identities?
It would.
They could end up being expelled.
I'm fine if I wear a hat to hide my ears.
I can hide my tail with a long skirt!
Miss Ryuzaki's tail
seems like it'd be discovered.
Not at all!
I'll do my best to hide it with a coat!
An outdoors Christmas date with Mr. Rei!
I'll do anything to make sure it happens!
Everyone's here?
We're handing out the rings.
Don't lose it by any means.
You won't be able to get back if you do.
Okay!
Shiranui Shrine Stop
Machi, you're gonna buy snacks?
That's right!
I can't forget to buy fresh pastries,
which I usually can't try!
I also want to eat some
limited-time ice creams!
What are you going to buy, Okonogi?
Um... steamed red bean buns?
Red bean buns?
Great choice.
Huh?
What's up, Mr. Hitoma?
Oh, nothing.
I was thinking of grabbing a pizza bun.
My mom loved red bean buns.
We're almost at the convenience store.
I'm getting nervous!
Christmas Chicken
So this is a convenience store!
Oh, wow. They even have a Christmas tree.
They do.
Mr. Hitoma!
Make sure you stay with me!
Me, too!
Hey, now!
I wouldn't want to get lost!
What if I end up getting stranded?
What?
Powder
Foundation
Look at all of these makeup products!
Let's hurry to the snack section!
Go on by yourself first!
I'm scared of ending up lost and alone!
Mr. Hitoma, let's go!
No! I need to see what colors
Mr. Rei prefers out of these!
Ms. Haruna, can you take care of Nezu?
C'mon, Mr. Hitoma! Let's go!
Okay, Miss Nezu. Come with me.
Fine, I guess...
Calpis
Water
What?!
All of the stuff here's for sale, right?
Yes. Everything with a price tag, that is.
Can I touch them?
You can, but try not to touch the ones
you're not buying too much.
Sure thing!
Wakaba, looking at fashion magazines?
Printed paper really is so nice.
It feels so much more real than
just reading it on your phone.
These pages, too, are bursting
with the essence of life.
Although I'm more beautiful.
Oh, that's right!
I'm out of packing tape!
And packaging twine!
Is now the time to stock up on those?
Huh? Where's Okonogi?
Ryuzaki, can I ask you to wait right here?
What? You'd leave me all alone?
So you've grown tired of me?!
No, not what I mean...
What's wrong, Mr. Hitoma?
Okonogi, where have you been?
Huh? Right here all along.
I see.
Try not to leave my sight,
or I'll be worried.
I suppose I could consider the idea.
Where'd you learn to talk like that?
So? Decided on what to buy?
A red bean bun.
Right. Anything else?
Nope.
All I want is the red bean bun.
I remember when shopping
seemed like a big adventure as a kid.
It sure did.
Huh? Where's Maki?
What?!
Okonogi?!
Did she get lost? Maki!
I'll look for her.
Ms. Haruna, keep an eye on the others.
Of course!
Okonogi! Okonogi!
Okonogi!
Mr. Hitoma...
What's wrong, Okonogi?
My red bean bun...
I dropped it...
That's too bad.
I was chasing the bun after I dropped it,
and then I lost sight of everyone.
I see. Let's go buy another someday.
Mr. Hitoma.
Is my mom doing well?
Sorry, I'm not privy to that information.
You've always lived with your mom, right?
I sure have.
Is your mom, well... the same as you?
Nope. My mom's a normal human.
I guess one of my ancestors was an oni.
Like what they call atavism?
Sometimes, you end up with
someone like me.
Mom told me her grandma was like me, too.
Someone who could see through lies.
Okonogi...
You can really tell when people are lying?
Mr. Hitoma, you don't lie very much.
What?
If only more people could be like you.
Then I could have lived with my mom.
You didn't want to
leave your mom, did you?
But I didn't want to be taken somewhere
scary, like my mom's grandma.
Somewhere scary?
I don't know the details,
but that's what Mom told me.
That's why I wanna be a human, like her.
Then it'll be okay to live with her.
Makes sense.
But why do you lie all the time?
Because I'm a bad person!
That's a lie.
I figured if I lied a lot, it'd be harder
to tell what was a lie and what wasn't.
In the end, it's my fault
for not being normal.
You're lying again.
Am I?
You are. I can tell.
Then maybe I am.
So you can really see through lies.
Well, I can see the colors
of everyone's voices.
Sometimes they're reddish,
and sometimes they're bluish.
Can you see my voice right now?
Yep. It's on the bluish side.
Usami's and Macchi's are
mostly blue as well.
Sometimes they're purple, though.
Why did you tell me about this?
You made me remember my mom.
At first, her voice was mostly blue.
But over time, it became redder
whenever she talked about me.
I couldn't help but feel sorry.
Mr. Hitoma. Why do humans have to lie?
It'd be better if they didn't.
Lying, huh?
It serves as protection, I guess.
Protecting what?
Yourself, or other people.
So it's not your fault, Okonogi.
Huh?
Um, what I mean is that
you're fine the way you are.
You sure are nice.
I wish I could be like you.
Why would you want to become like me?
Wouldn't Ms. Haruna be closer
in terms of her age and tastes?
That's true.
Ms. Mirai's a lot more like me.
Maybe that's why I admire you so much.
Huh?
I wonder what Ms. Mirai's
trying to protect.
What?
People lie to protect
something, don't they?
Mr. Hitoma!
I'm glad you're all right.
I was so worried!
I'm sorry! I was spacing out.
I wonder what Ms. Mirai's
trying to protect.
People lie to protect
something, don't they?
Ms. Mirai!
What is it?
Can I pat your head?
What? Again?
Crouch down!
All right.
Ms. Mirai, you're a good girl.
Don't be too hard on yourself.
Can I give you a hug as well?
Do as you like.
Ms. Mirai.
You're a big liar
whenever it comes to Mr. Hitoma.
What's wrong?
I'll head back first and
tell the principal what happened.
Ms. Haruna!
Okonogi, what did you say to Ms. Haruna?
I don't think you'd
understand, Mr. Hitoma.
Since you're bluish.
You'd only get it if you were
pure red, like the two of us.
Next Episode:
The Misanthrope and the Nigh Future